- [Instructor] Okay, so let's go ahead and install
the main components that will allow us to build
a full stack application
and then generate our first React application
and the folder structure.
So the first thing that you need is Node.js.
That's going to be the base of our backend.
So you want to make sure you have it installed
inside of your system.
So there's two ways to actually install Node.js.
There's the NVM way, which you can actually control
what version of node you want very easily
through the command here.
So if you want to test NVM,
you can go to github.com/nvm/sh/nvm,
and then follow the instructions to do the installation
inside of your system right here.
If you want to use the typical way of installing node,
you can literally go here,
and I would recommend to use the LTS version
because the other versions are the current versions,
but they haven't been tested thoroughly.
So I would recommend the LTS version.
It will download the version for your operating system,
or you can literally go here in other downloads,
select your operating system,
and then install whatever version that you want.
So that's the way to install Node.js.
Once you have an install, you're good to go.
And we can close this, I'll get to VS Code in a second,
but I'm just going to open a terminal for the time being.
So I'm going to go to my desktop first.
So go to desktop and do an ls.
So we're all good.
Okay, so on the desktop, what you would do now,
just to make sure you have Node.js,
what you would do is do node/version.
And if you see a version installed here,
that means that you have node installed.
So at least you have that.
So what we're going to do now is create
inside of a folder, the backend folder,
and the front end folder.
So we're going to create a brand new application with React.
So what I'm going to do now is basically right click
on the desktop, create the soccer folder,
soccer, and then inside of that folder
I'm going to create the backend
where we'll have our node server.
So we have the backend and we're going to have the front end.
So what I'm going to do now is go into that folder
inside of a terminal.
So I'm going to close that terminal, bring that app directly
inside of VS Code, and now I have the backend,
and now I'm going to be able to create the front end.
So I'm going to open up a terminal by clicking terminal,
new or using the shortcuts control grave like so.
And we're going to now create our React application.
Now a note to anybody that is familiar with React,
as of the last version for Create React app,
it is no longer maintained.
So you have multiple options
when you want to create a React application now.
So you can use Remix, you can use Next.js
and you can use Vite.
And I'm a big fan of Vite
because it creates applications very quickly
without a lot of extra stuff that we need.
So the way to install an application with Vite,
you do npm create vite@latest
and it's going to create a Vite project.
Now, if you don't have Vite installed,
it's going to say, well,
you want to install, you say Yes,
and now you name your project.
So again, you're doing this in the root
of the soccer folder, which means that whatever you're going
to create here is going to be added inside of that folder.
So in this case, what I want to name this is front end,
and now you have a few selections.
In this case, we're doing a React application,
but you can select anything else.
I would recommend because this course is on React
to select React.
And then if you're familiar with TypeScript,
you can use TypeScript.
If you're familiar with JavaScript
or prefer JavaScript, you can use JavaScript.
The SWC is basically a transpiler.
This is really new, so I wouldn't use it for a course,
but you can use it for your own goods if you want to.
I'm not going to use it here, so I'm going to use JavaScript.
And now the front end application is created.
So it basically created the folder structure that we need
for our React application.
We'll work with it as we go,
and you have all the limits that you need.
The one thing that you will notice versus creating
a React application the old way is that this is much faster,
and this is probably why it's called Vite.
That's French for speed.
So what am I going to do now?
You need to do an npm inside of the front end.
So let's go and see the front end.
Do an npm install like so,
and this is the process that Vite actually skips,
but even there, it actually is much faster
because the packages that are required
for Vite are much smaller.
I built several applications with Vite
and I've been really impressed with
how fast this thing goes.
Now all you have to do to run the applications
is do an npm run dev
and go to local host 5173,
and this is what you should see.
So Vite + React, and then you can test accounts here.
And this is basically the setup for our application.
So we have our front end that is ready,
and then we're going to be working on the backend
over the next few videos.
So see you in a bit.